Guide to the Ben Stein Papers
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
Ben Stein papers
1920-1972
University of Washington Libraries Special Collections Box 352900 Seattle, WA 98195-2900
1916
1916-001
Stein, Ben,$dapproximately 1890-
0.94 cubic feet (2 boxes) plus 2 audio cassettes
Tape-recorded interview of an immigrant from Russia concerning life in Seattle
Born around 1890 in the Russian-controlled Belarusian city of Minsk, Ben Stein arrived as an immigrant to the United States in 1915. Initially landing in Seattle, he soon traveled east across the country and tried his hand at a series of professions. Stein never returned to Russia, but instead chose to settle in the Seattle area for the remainder of his life. After working in the luggage business for a time, Stein began to sell insurance in Seattle with his cousin, M.N. Ketzlach. Though his work as an insurance agent provided him with his primary source of income, the true focus of his energy was his involvement with Seattle's Jewish community. Stein served as the financial secretary for the Seattle branch of the Workmen's Circle, an organization that provided fiscal, cultural, and educational support to Jewish citizens in the area.
The collection contains general correspondence, academic work, and journals that belonged to Ben Stein, as well as a tape-recorded interview with Stein in 1972 that discusses his life and his time with the Workmen's Circle organization.
Listen to the audio recording of this interview on the Libraries Digital Collections site.
No restrictions on access.
Donated by Ben Stein, May 9, 1972
Workmen's Circle/Der Arbeter Ring Branch 304 photograph collection (PH0769)
Workmen's Circle/Der Arbeter Ring Branch 304 records (Manuscript collection 1859)
The visual materials that form part of this collection are described and indexed in
A Guide to the
.
Stein, Ben,$dapproximately 1890- $vArchives; Washington State Jewish Archives (University of Washington)
Personal Papers/Corporate Records; Jewish Americans; Russian Americans; Sound Recordings; Oral Histories; Seattle
- Ben Stein Papers, Series 1
  - General Correspondence, 1920-1972 (Box-folder 1/1)
  - School Papers, 1920-1924 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Drawing, undated (Box-folder 1/3)
  - Notebook, undated (Box-folder 1/4)
  - Diary, 1929-1930 (Box-folder 1/5)
  - Record Books of Stein and Ketzlach Insurance Co., 1939-1965 (Box 2)
- Ben Stein Interview, Series 2
  - Audio Interview with Ben Stein, Part 1, 1972 (Cassette 1)
  - Audio Interview with Ben Stein, Part 2, 1972 (Cassette 2)